elthamleisurecentre.com.au 2019-03-17

# Privacy policy |

  1. **Protecting Privacy**

Your privacy is important to Aligned Leisure. This privacy policy provides information about the personal information that Aligned Leisure collects and the ways in which Aligned Leisure may use, hold and disclose this personal information.

  2. **Aligned Leisure Privacy Policy**

This policy describes the way Aligned Leisure will collect, hold and disclose personal information. Personal information is information that identifies you or could identify you. Aligned Leisure are subject to the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), including the Australian Privacy Principles. Aligned Leisure reserve the right to vary their privacy policy from time to time, by posting an updated policy accessible via Aligned Leisure’s website.

The protection of personal information is critical to Aligned Leisure’s relationship with customers, employees and members. Any personal information received in connection with an Aligned Leisure product or service, or in the conduct of Aligned Leisure’s business, will be treated in line with the principles set out in this document.

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, personal information may mean some or all of the following: a customer’s name, contact details, date of birth, emergency contact details, bank account and/or credit card details, tax file number, student identification details, concession details, Medicare number, social security number, employment details, payment history and other sensitive information.

  3. **Cookies**

Aligned Leisure may use tracking technologies such as “cookies” or web beacons. A cookie is a small text file that Aligned Leisure may place on your computer. Usually, cookies are used as a means for our websites to remember your preferences and are thus designed to improve your experience of our website. Cookies may collect and store personal information about you. Web Beacon is designed to provide information related to your access to websites, when you browse websites, open or preview an HTML-formatted email.

You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent. Each browser is different, so check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your preferences.  It is possible to set the browser to refuse tracking technologies such as cookies or web beacons.

If you disable the use of cookies on your web browser or reject specific cookies from our website or linked sites then you may not be able to gain access to all of the content and facilities on Aligned Leisure’s website.

  4. **Website Analytics**

When you visit and browse our website, both the website host and some third party service providers may collect information for statistical, reporting and maintenance purposes.

Subject to the terms of this privacy policy, this information is used to administer and improve the performance of Aligned Leisure and will not be used to identify you. The information may include:

  1. the number of users visiting our website and the number of pages viewed;
  2. the date, time and duration of a visit;
  3. visiting patterns of individuals;
  4. the IP address of your computer; and
  5. the path taken through our website.

Aligned Leisure will use website analytic services to help analyse how you use our website. Website Analytics generate statistical and other information about website use by means including but not limited to cookies which are stored on users’ computers. The information generated is used to create reports about the use of our website. Our third party providers of these services may store this information.  Aligned Leisure will not (and will not allow any third party to) use Website Analytics to track or to collect any personally identifiable information of visitors to Aligned Leisure’s website. Aligned Leisure will not associate any data gathered from Aligned Leisure with any personally identifying information from any source as part of Aligned Leisure’s use of Website Analytics.

Aligned Leisure treats personal information that may be obtained through cookies, web beacons and any other information supplied to us (for example if you send us an email) in accordance with this privacy policy.

  5. **Use and disclosure of Information Collected**

Aligned Leisure will not collect or monitor any personal information about an individual without their consent.  Personal information that is collected will be what is provided voluntarily by a customer, member or prospective member. Personal information is collected so that we can adequately provide service to our customers.  Aligned Leisure may from time to time use the information for marketing to you or for any other purpose permitted under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).

Where possible, we will endeavour to provide you with anonymity if you so desire.  In certain situations, however, we can only deal with individuals who have identified themselves to Aligned Leisure.

When a product or service is purchased from Aligned Leisure, personal information may be requested in order to provide the requested service or product, to provide updated information, or to advise of other relevant products of Aligned Leisure or our partners, which we believe may be relevant to you.  You are not obligated to provide personal information however failure to do so may result in Aligned Leisure being unable to provide services or products to you.

Personal information is collected directly from customers when they complete and submit application forms or information forms that relate to products or services that are provided by Aligned Leisure. This can be done in person, on line, via our website or on the phone via one of our staff.

  6. **Sensitive Information**

As a result of the products and services that Aligned Leisure offer, we may also be required to collect sensitive information.  For the purposes of this Privacy Policy sensitive information means the information a customer has disclosed to us about their physical and mental health and wellbeing or other personal information that may be referred to as “sensitive”.

Sensitive information will only ever be used for providing services to customer. Such information will not be used or disclosed for any other purposes without consent, except in exceptional cases when disclosure may be required by law or is necessary to protect the rights or property of Aligned Leisure, or any member of the public, or to lessen a serious threat to a person’s health or safety. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy sensitive information is a subset of personal information.

Some sensitive information must be retained by Aligned Leisure.  Health information must be retained for 7 years following the last occasion on which service was provided. Where information was collected while the individual was a child it shall be retained until the individual is 25 years old, or for 7 years whichever is the greater. Your personal information that is no longer required will be de-identified or destroyed. In many circumstances, however it will be kept for marketing purposes as you will have consented to that in writing with us.

  7. **Information from Third Parties**

During the course of business, Aligned Leisure may also collect personal information that is given to them by a third party (for example, information that is on a publicly maintained record, information that is passed from a previous manager of facilities that Aligned Leisure take over management of). This information forms part of the personal information described in this policy. Aligned Leisure will not intentionally solicit personal information that is unintentionally disclosed.

  8. **Information Security**

Aligned Leisure will take reasonable steps to protect all personal information within their direct control from misuse, interference, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. Aligned Leisure will take reasonable steps to hold information securely in electronic or physical form in access controlled premises or in electronic databases requiring logins and passwords.

Electronic personal and sensitive information is stored in a secure, Australian-based data centre.

Only Aligned Leisure authorised personnel have access to information and information will only be used for approved purposes.

  9. **Contacting Aligned Leisure Regarding Access & Correction and Privacy Complaints**

An individual may:

  1. request access to and seek the correction of their personal information held by Aligned Leisure at any time;
  2. make a complaint in relation to a breach of privacy; or
  3. submit a query or concern about this privacy policy

by contacting Aligned Leisure [info@alignedleisure.com.au](mailto:info@alignedleisure.com.au)

Access – You will be required to provide proof of identity in order to obtain access to your personal information. Aligned Leisure may charge a fee where access is provided. Aligned Leisure may refuse to provide access if permitted to do so by law. Aligned Leisure aims to provide access to your personal information within 30 days of a valid request.

Complaints – At all times, privacy complaints:

  1. will be treated seriously;
  2. will be dealt with promptly;
  3. will be dealt with in a confidential manner; and
  4. will not affect your existing obligations or affect the commercial arrangements between you and Aligned Leisure.

Aligned Leisure’s Privacy Officer will commence an investigation into your complaint. You will be informed of the outcome of your complaint within a reasonable period of time following completion of the investigation.

  10. **Transfer of data due to change in management**

Aligned Leisure operates recreation, leisure and sports facilities on behalf of local governments.  From time to time, Aligned Leisure may commence or complete contractual requirements for the management of particular facilities.  In the process of completing a contract, Aligned Leisure may be required to provide the owners of the facilities with personal details that relate to our customers.  These personal details may include a customer’s name, contact details, date of birth, emergency contact details, bank account and/or credit card details, tax file number, student identification details, concession details, Medicare number, social security number, employment details, payment history and other sensitive information.

It is a contractual requirement of managing facilities that we make this information available.  In the event that any information made available due to the above circumstances is to be passed to facility owners, Aligned Leisure will manage the transfer of data in line with the principles of this privacy policy.
